# RAMYA MOHAN

# PROJECT MANAGER | DATA ANALYST

508-579-1560 ramya.tammisetti@gmail.com

San Jose, CA

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramya-tammisettimohan

https://tammisettir.github.io/resume

## SUMMARY

Accomplished IT professional in the Healthcare IT industry. Over 6 years of experience in project management, data analytics, and software development within the healthcare IT industry. Proven ability to lead and execute complex projects from conception to completion. Looking for a role in data analytics.

# **CORE COMPETENCIES**

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS Data Analytics | Data Driven Decision Making | Complex Project Management | Risk Management |

Client Relations & Communications | Prompt Engineering

**TECHNICAL SKILLS** Data Analysis | Data Mining | Tableau | PowerBI | Machine Learning | Python - numpy, pandas | SQL | Git

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **ECLINICALWORKS**

Project Manager | March 2022 - December 2022

- eClinicalWorks(eCW) is the largest cloud based EHR software in the U.S.
- · Delivered multiple complex projects, beating the estimated timeline and within the planned budget by actively managing the project using the AGILE framework.
- Improved the product definition by communicating data-driven insights to the product development teams. Increased customer satisfaction through customized eCW solutions.
- · Enhanced client satisfaction with strategic advisement on eCW solution packages tailored to clinic needs.
- · Aligned project goals and implementation by ensuring constant communication between all stakeholders.
- Improved implementation and training processes by developing robust documentation.

Software Training Specialist | November 2019 - March 2022

- · Improved customer satisfaction on EMR training programs for over 200 clients by customizing training programs and orienting the focus to be more hands on
- · Achieved significant decrease in user reported issues by analyzing usage patterns, challenges, and pain points and providing actionable recommendations to product teams.
- · Improved quality of training programs by developing a comprehensive database of training materials, incorporating customer feedback, and tracking performance metrics
- Maintained confidentiality by adhering to strict HIPAA and Compliance standards

Analytics Intern | May 2017 - August 2017

· Supported eCW in their predictive analytics projects by developing a database in R that linked medical test data to chronic conditions

### AMERICAN RED CROSS

Lab Technician | January 2015 - July 2015

Achieved stringent quality standard set by the company by managing lab inventory and conducting complex DNA extraction procedures

# BETH ISRAEL DEACONESS MEDICAL CENTER

Research Assistant | January 2014 - July 2014

· Assisted in pioneering research on circadian rhythms, contributing to published findings that influenced industry standards.

#### RELEVANT PROJECTS

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION**

Chronic Risk Assessment - Developed a comprehensive data linkage system using PostgreSQL, enhancing the predictive analytics capabilities for chronic disease management.

Covid Analysis - Supported public health decisions by conducting a detailed analysis of Covid-19 data to derive actionable insights on transmission pattern

Quality Improvement - Enhanced eCW EMR systems by developing eCQMs test cases

Data Quality - Improved EMR UI wby validating user input

Workflow Improvements - Identified improvements in key clinical workflows by documenting eCW interfaces

Real Time Dashboard - Improved coffee shop sales by identifying influential factors by creating a dashboard of interactive visualizations

CERTIFICATION IN AI POWERED DATA ANALYTICS 2023 - 2024 | California Institute of Career Development

MASTERS OF COMPUTER SCIENCE 2016 - 2018 | University of Massachusetts Amherst

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE - BIOLOGY 2011 - 2015 | Northeastern University

NATIONAL MERIT SCHOLARSHIP

2011- 2015 | National Merit Finalist, full tuition scholarship to NEU